# Lydia M. González Esparza

iOS Developer m linkedin.com/in/lydiam

<u>lydiamariong@gmail.com</u> <u>linkedin.com/in/lydiamariong</u> <u>GitHub.com/LaLydi</u>

#### **ABOUT**

Organized, detailed-oriented, and collaborative iOS developer with 3 years of professional experience working on coding, testing, and maintenance in native mobile-app environments. Eager to learn and contribute to the app's growth by creating clean and efficient code. Innovative and creative problem solver with a keen eye for design.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### iOS Developer, JAAK — May 2022 - Present

- <u>JAAK</u> designs ethical software solutions for clients to adopt AI and ML technologies to improve experience and security.
- Developed native packages from scratch based on in-house ML models to reuse in applications.
- Documented packages for future implementations.
- Designed and developed demo applications implementing the frameworks to attract prospective clients.
- Deployed applications through TestFlight for QA testing phases.
- Technologies:
  - Swift for development
  - o Git repositories for version control
  - TestFlight for QA testing
  - o AVKit, animations, and CoreML for custom views
  - Used MVVM, Delegation, Singleton, Observer, and Coordinator patterns for app development

## iOS Developer, Farside Labs — April 2021 - August 2021

- Clift is an online gift registry for weddings.
- Worked in overall app maintenance, feature creation, and code refactoring.
- Designed views necessary for new features.
- Participated in QA testing of the app.
- Technologies:
  - Swift and Objective-C for development
  - o Git repositories for version control
  - Auto-layout for interface building
  - Adobe XD for UX design

### iOS Developer, Piso 13 — May 2019 - January 2021

- Opus One Mobile: Daily Planner and Opus One for Mac are a to-do manager based on Franklin Covey's planner system and The 7 Habits of Highly Effective People.
- Worked in overall app maintenance, improvement, and feature creation always promoting best practices and standards.
- Designed banners for the AppStore's Feature App section.
- Collaborated in the upkeeping of the app's design.
- Technologies:
  - Swift and Objective-C for development
  - Git repositories for version control
  - Core Data framework for data modeling
  - Auto-layout for interface building
  - o Photoshop and Illustrator for design

# TECH SKILLS

## Languages

- Swift
- Objective-C
- F
- Python

#### **Frameworks**

- UIKit
- Core Data
- CloudKit
- Realm
- Cocoa Touch
- CoreML

#### Tools

- Xcode
- Git
- Adobe Suite

#### Soft Skills

- Agile project methodology
- Research
- Technical writing

## **EDUCATION**

## University of Alberta — September 2020 -Present

- Master of Education, degree in Measurement, Evaluation, and Data Science
- Graduation: Summer 2023

# Tecnológico de Monterrey — August 2014 - December 2018

 Bachelor of Engineering, degree in Information Technologies and Communication.